<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Cory McCartan</title>
    <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Cory McCartan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Our Unions</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</guid>
      <description> Harvard graduate student workers on the picket lines, December 2019.
  how unions are on the decline but also resurging. actually poorly understood from a structural persp. good time to ask: what do unions actually look like in 2019? Like so much else in America, unions diverged from their -- There are 5 million union members in the United States.   Text 2  Text 3  Text 4    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Democratic candidates are most electable?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</guid>
      <description>The interactive below accompanies this article I wrote for the Washington Post. The article has some other figures, explains the motivation, and provides a less-detailed overview of the methodology than that provided below.
If the national popular vote were  50.0% Democratic and 50.0% Republican, we&#39;d expect the candidates to win these states:  (Drag the vertical line)
    Why does this approach work? While head-to-head polls are generally not very predictive, the demographic patterns they reveal turn out to be much more durable, as the figure below illustrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 U.S. House Predictions</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</guid>
      <description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ messageStyle: &#34;none&#34;, CommonHTML: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, tex2jax: {inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;]]} });         How the odds have changed  The model is continuously updated with new polling data and approval ratings. As new information comes in, the odds may shift towards one party or another. Additionally, as we get closer to the election, there is less uncertainty in the result, since there is less time for a large shift in public opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>