<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Cory McCartan</title>
    <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Cory McCartan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Presidential Forecast</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/president-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/president-20/</guid>
      <description>2020 FORECASTS  President House      NOTE  This model relies on GDP forecasts made by the New York branch of the Federal Reserve. On Friday, April 17, the Fed branch revised its estimate of second-quarter GDP growth sharply downwards, causing the model to adjust its structural forecast in favor of Joe Biden, which greatly increased his estimated chances of winning the election.  The pandemic and its economic fallout have caused a lot to change very quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 House Forecast</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-20/</guid>
      <description>2020 FORECASTS  President House       What does a  chance feel like? Click the button below to randomly simulate a hypothetical election. While the Democrats may be favored to win, there&#39;s a lot of variation in how many seats they may gain or lose. Simulate an election  
How the odds have changed The model works by using economic indicators, structural factors (like whether it is a midterm year, or the party that controls the White House), and national polling data to estimate what the nationwide popular vote (adding up all the votes for each party in all 435 districts) and the seat breakdown will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization and the American Electorate</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch the steadiness of Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s job approval numbers&amp;mdash;43% of voters approving and 52% disapproving, for most of the last year&amp;mdash;and not be convinced that Americans are deeply polarized: one half watches Fox news, the other half watches MSNBC; one half hates immigrants, the other embraces them; one half thinks climate change is a hoax, the other wants to pass the Green New Deal. Neither half wants their children to marry a member of the other half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Industrial Union Grand?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</guid>
      <description>AFL-CIO headquarters, Washington, D.C.
  
There is power there is power in a band of workingmen,
When they stand hand in hand,
That&amp;rsquo;s a power, that&amp;rsquo;s a power
That must rule in every land—
One Industrial Union Grand.
 &amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;There is Power in a Union,&amp;rdquo; Joe Hill   “Big Labor’s Big Shrink,” gloated the headline of a Wall Street Journal editorial last year, using Joe Biden’s presidential campaign kickoff at a union hall as an opportunity to trot out its tried-and-true union-bashing lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Democratic candidates are most electable?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</guid>
      <description>The interactive below accompanies this article I wrote for the Washington Post. The article has some other figures, explains the motivation, and provides a less-detailed overview of the methodology than that provided below.
If the national popular vote were  50.0% Democratic and 50.0% Republican, we&#39;d expect the candidates to win these states:  (Drag the vertical line)
    Why does this approach work? While head-to-head polls are generally not very predictive, the demographic patterns they reveal turn out to be much more durable, as the figure below illustrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 U.S. House Predictions</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</guid>
      <description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ messageStyle: &#34;none&#34;, CommonHTML: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, tex2jax: {inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;]]} });         How the odds have changed  The model is continuously updated with new polling data and approval ratings. As new information comes in, the odds may shift towards one party or another. Additionally, as we get closer to the election, there is less uncertainty in the result, since there is less time for a large shift in public opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>