<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Cory McCartan</title>
    <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Cory McCartan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://corymccartan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Election Forecasts</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/election-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/election-2020/</guid>
      <description>House Forecast &amp;raquo;  Presidential Forecast (Coming Soon)  Senate Forecast (Someday)   .promo { width: 100%; display: flex; background: white; font-size: 20pt; margin-bottom: 1em; border-radius: 8px; border-bottom: 2px solid #aaa; } .promo img { width: 50%; max-width: 3in; border-radius: 8px 0 0 7px; } .promo a { padding: 1em; margin: auto; text-decoration: none; } .promo a:hover { color: black; text-decoration: underline; } .promo a.broken:hover { cursor: default; text-decoration: none; } @media screen and (max-width: 540px) { .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 House Forecast</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-20/</guid>
      <description>What does a  chance feel like? Click the button below to randomly simulate a hypothetical election. While the Democrats may be favored to win, there&#39;s a lot of variation in how many seats they may gain or lose. Simulate an election  
How the odds have changed The model works by using economic indicators, structural factors (like whether it is a midterm year, or the party that controls the White House), and national polling data to estimate what the nationwide popular vote (adding up all the votes for each party in all 435 districts) and the seat breakdown will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other March Madness</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/03/dst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/03/dst/</guid>
      <description>Should this be the last daylight savings? The time zone shift is an excellent opportunity to look at daylight patterns across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nevada Caucuses</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-nevada-caucuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-nevada-caucuses/</guid>
      <description>Caucuses have a distinct advantage over primaries, which are conducted by ballot: after an initial tally of candidates’ support, voters can realign themselves into new groups before the final count. This realignment process can provide valuable insight into the preferences of voters, and help us understand how the race might change if more candidates start to drop out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a Streak?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/weather/</guid>
      <description>Streaks are an important part of how we experience a place&#39;s weather: it matters not just how hot it gets, or how much it rains, but also how long these kinds of weather stick around. Mathematically, one way to understand these patterns is through Markov chains. Thinking of weather in this way can reveal some interesting patterns, and confirm some stereotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geography of Political Differences</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-geography-of-political-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-geography-of-political-differences/</guid>
      <description>While we’re all familiar with the usual red-blue map of state partisan preference, things get a little more interesting when we look at states&amp;rsquo; views on economic and social issues separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization and the American Electorate</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch the steadiness of Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s job approval numbers&amp;mdash;43% of voters approving and 52% disapproving, for most of the last year&amp;mdash;and not be convinced that Americans are deeply polarized: one half watches Fox news, the other half watches MSNBC; one half hates immigrants, the other embraces them; one half thinks climate change is a hoax, the other wants to pass the Green New Deal. Neither half wants their children to marry a member of the other half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Industrial Union Grand?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</guid>
      <description>AFL-CIO headquarters, Washington, D.C.
  
There is power there is power in a band of workingmen,
When they stand hand in hand,
That&amp;rsquo;s a power, that&amp;rsquo;s a power
That must rule in every land—
One Industrial Union Grand.
 &amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;There is Power in a Union,&amp;rdquo; Joe Hill   “Big Labor’s Big Shrink,” gloated the headline of a Wall Street Journal editorial last year, using Joe Biden’s presidential campaign kickoff at a union hall as an opportunity to trot out its tried-and-true union-bashing lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Continental Divide</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2019/12/the-continental-divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 16:15:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2019/12/the-continental-divide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The standard U.S. map shows states laid out in two dimensions, but doesn&#39;t
convey any information about the crucial third dimension: altitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Democratic candidates are most electable?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</guid>
      <description>The interactive below accompanies this article I wrote for the Washington Post. The article has some other figures, explains the motivation, and provides a less-detailed overview of the methodology than that provided below.
If the national popular vote were  50.0% Democratic and 50.0% Republican, we&#39;d expect the candidates to win these states:  (Drag the vertical line)
    Why does this approach work? While head-to-head polls are generally not very predictive, the demographic patterns they reveal turn out to be much more durable, as the figure below illustrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 U.S. House Predictions</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</guid>
      <description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ messageStyle: &#34;none&#34;, CommonHTML: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, tex2jax: {inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;]]} });         How the odds have changed  The model is continuously updated with new polling data and approval ratings. As new information comes in, the odds may shift towards one party or another. Additionally, as we get closer to the election, there is less uncertainty in the result, since there is less time for a large shift in public opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37 Supreme Court Justices on a Plane</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2017/10/37-supreme-court-justices-on-a-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2017/10/37-supreme-court-justices-on-a-plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common measure of Supreme Court justice ideology are the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mqscores.lsa.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;Martin&amp;ndash;Quinn scores&lt;/a&gt;, developed by the
eponymous political scientists.  Since their &lt;a href=&#34;https://mqscores.lsa.umich.edu/media/pa02.pdf&#34;&gt;original publication in
2002&lt;/a&gt;, the scores have been
widely used, in political science and in the media, to place justices on
a left&amp;ndash;right political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swirling Fractals</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2015/04/swirling-fractals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2015/04/swirling-fractals/</guid>
      <description>Corresponding to each point in and around the Mandelbrot set is a Julia set. If we start with a point near the origin, and move it in a circle around the main bulb of the Mandelbrot set, the series of corresponding Julia sets morph beautifully into one another.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>