<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Cory McCartan</title>
    <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Cory McCartan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://corymccartan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geography of Political Differences</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-geography-of-political-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2020/02/the-geography-of-political-differences/</guid>
      <description>I recently examined the political views of ordinary voters, and made a lot of comparisons across income groups, political parties, education, and race. One factor I didn&#39;t look at, though, was geography. While we’re all familiar with the usual red-blue map of state partisan preference, things get a little more interesting when we look at states&amp;rsquo; views on economic and social issues separately.
Read: Polarization and the American Electorate &amp;raquo;  Using data from the Cooperative Congressional Election Study, which asks voters about their views on a range of policy questions, we can assign each voter a social and economic score, ranging from –100 (most liberal) to 100 (most conservative).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization and the American Electorate</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electorate-2020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch the steadiness of Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s job approval numbers&amp;mdash;43% of voters approving and 52% disapproving, for most of the last year&amp;mdash;and not be convinced that Americans are deeply polarized: one half watches Fox news, the other half watches MSNBC; one half hates immigrants, the other embraces them; one half thinks climate change is a hoax, the other wants to pass the Green New Deal. Neither half wants their children to marry a member of the other half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Industrial Union Grand?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/unions-2019/</guid>
      <description>AFL-CIO headquarters, Washington, D.C.
  
There is power there is power in a band of workingmen,
When they stand hand in hand,
That&amp;rsquo;s a power, that&amp;rsquo;s a power
That must rule in every land—
One Industrial Union Grand.
 &amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;There is Power in a Union,&amp;rdquo; Joe Hill   “Big Labor’s Big Shrink,” gloated the headline of a Wall Street Journal editorial last year, using Joe Biden’s presidential campaign kickoff at a union hall as an opportunity to trot out its tried-and-true union-bashing lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One State, Two States, Low State, High State</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2019/12/one-state-two-states-low-state-high-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 16:15:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2019/12/one-state-two-states-low-state-high-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The standard U.S. map shows states laid out in two dimensions, but doesn&#39;t
convey any information about the crucial third dimension: altitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Democratic candidates are most electable?</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/electability-2020/</guid>
      <description>The interactive below accompanies this article I wrote for the Washington Post. The article has some other figures, explains the motivation, and provides a less-detailed overview of the methodology than that provided below.
If the national popular vote were  50.0% Democratic and 50.0% Republican, we&#39;d expect the candidates to win these states:  (Drag the vertical line)
    Why does this approach work? While head-to-head polls are generally not very predictive, the demographic patterns they reveal turn out to be much more durable, as the figure below illustrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 U.S. House Predictions</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/projects/us-house-2018/</guid>
      <description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ messageStyle: &#34;none&#34;, CommonHTML: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, tex2jax: {inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;]]} });         How the odds have changed  The model is continuously updated with new polling data and approval ratings. As new information comes in, the odds may shift towards one party or another. Additionally, as we get closer to the election, there is less uncertainty in the result, since there is less time for a large shift in public opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37 Supreme Court Justices on a Plane</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2017/10/37-supreme-court-justices-on-a-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2017/10/37-supreme-court-justices-on-a-plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common measure of Supreme Court justice ideology are the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mqscores.lsa.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;Martin&amp;ndash;Quinn scores&lt;/a&gt;, developed by the
eponymous political scientists.  Since their &lt;a href=&#34;https://mqscores.lsa.umich.edu/media/pa02.pdf&#34;&gt;original publication in
2002&lt;/a&gt;, the scores have been
widely used, in political science and in the media, to place justices on
a left&amp;ndash;right political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swirling Fractals</title>
      <link>https://corymccartan.github.io/2015/04/swirling-fractals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corymccartan.github.io/2015/04/swirling-fractals/</guid>
      <description>Corresponding to each point in and around the Mandelbrot set is a Julia set. If we start with a point near the origin, and move it in a circle around the main bulb of the Mandelbrot set, the series of corresponding Julia sets morph beautifully into one another.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>